That's amazing! It's a cup now!
It's a cup now?
Yeah!
Where's the pizza now!
Yeah, where's the pizza now!
Ask him!
Yes!
Okay!
What do you think?
Dahn!
Dah!
It's a beautiful day!
It's so peaceful!
Amazing!
It's a pleasant day!
It's nice.
Oh, hello.
Hello.
Good evening
I'm here today in Yamagata City, Yamagata Prefecture
Yay!
Hey, hey, Mi-chan. What's up?
Isn't this your first time in Yamagata this year?
Ha! Sure is!
It might be my first time!
Wow!
So this time
In Qijumen Busan
I'd like to experience a mountain pass!
Wow!
Then I'll tell you today's goal.
Yes, please!
Well, I'd like to do pottery as usual!
Oh!
I'm going to try not to get my hair caught in my hands while I'm pottering.
It's so silky.
Yes, sir.
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
I want to make sure it doesn't!
Please pay attention to those two things and watch that video.
Please.
Now, I'm going to hypnotize you.
Let's go!
Yes, we're in.
We're in.
Okay, now, I'm going to put on the ceramic vines.
I'm going to put on an apron
I'm going to put on an apron.
Yay!
Oh, here's an apron!
Let's choose one!
You can choose any one you like.
Oh, really?
I'm so happy.
I don't know what I'll do.
I'm pretty sure we won't wear the same one.
That's true.
I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know.
What is it? What does it say?
Woof! Woof!
He's so cute!
It's "Woof woof.
He's so cute.
Keep you sleeping until you get up
What does it say?
I don't know.
Peach Blossom is fun.
I'm sure it is.
I don't know what to do.
I don't know if I like it or not.
Do what you like.
Okay, I'll do it.
It's decided.
I'll go with this one.
Today's outfit.
Here's today's outfit.
I'll do my best.
Here I am.
It looks good on you.
Really?
He's so cute.
You look great.
Thank you.
Marine.
Marine Passion.
It looks good on you.
Glad you like it.
Now I'd like to call the teacher for today's pottery experience.
Let's start at the beginning!
Seino
Takahashi-sensei!
I'm looking forward to working with you.
But you know, we were so whipped, we thought it was a chair at first.
Yeah, I tried to sit down.
So we'll just have to work a little harder.
Let's go for it. Let's go for it.
I'm gonna try to impress people with this, and, you know, I'm gonna try to be a potter.
Let's go for it.
AO.
Oh, please.
And I'll hand them out.
And then I'll ask them to decide what they want to make.
I don't know what I'm going to do.
I don't know.
Okay.
Now I'd like to announce what we're going to make and what it will look like.
Then, Hikaru Tsukiki, please.
Yes, I will make
A cup.
Yes, please.
I want to make a Japanese cup like this.
Okay.
I, Miyu Fujita, would like to make a plate.
Oh!
Yes, like this.
I'll do my best.
I'll do my best!
Okay, let's get started.
Yes, sir.
Then, first of all...
Put a little bit of the cup in the handle.
How much?
In the dumpling part.
Do I put a lot in?
Wow!
Is it soft?
So soft!
More than an earlobe?
That's about right.
Ears are soft.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Do you want to put something on the plate?
Yes, sir.
What do you want to put on it?
Ears?
Oh, earlobes.
Earlobes.
I'll do that.
Earlobe.
Then I'd like to take as much as I need, so please tear off a little bit.
Okay.
Put the clay on the board like this.
How big is an earlobe?
A real earlobe.
Earlobe.
Oh, it's so soft!
Earlobe
But it's really only an earlobe, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
That's an earlobe.
That's amazing, I've never touched it before.
Now, if you'll leave it on the board.
First of all, let's make the noodles round and round.
Tap it a little bit like you're making a rice ball grip.
Let's make it into a round ball.
That's right, that's right.
Oh, it's so hard!
So hard, so hard, so hard!
I don't know why it's so hard for me, too.
It's so hard!
Are you okay?
That's why they picked me.
What? I might have a side.
When it's almost round, it's okay.
Yes, ma'am.
And then the server said...
I'll wait.
Is this a good time?
Yes, it's okay.
Then the platter puts the board on the potter's wheel.
Okay.
And can I have this one attached a little bit?
Yes, I'll turn it a little bit at a time and then stick it back together.
Okay.
Now, let's tap this clay in the middle, turning it a little bit at a time.
Huh?
You can turn it slowly.
I'm going to make a hole in the middle with my thumb.
Yes, sir.
Is it going to work?
Yes.
I'm going to drill this hole.
Punch the hole.
Yes, sir.
Leave about a fingernail root.
That's not easy.
What? What do you mean?
It's okay.
What do you mean? What do you mean?
Then, little by little, the outside fingers...
All the way out?
Yes, yes, a little bit at a time.
I can respond.
Yes, yes.
What? It's hard.
It's hard!
It's cute!
Give me a light.
It's too hard!
I want to be like him.
I want to be like you.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, no.
Oh, wow, that's great!
I got something!
Oh!
Then let's write a newspaper once.
Yes, sir.
That's great!
It's already a cup.
Already a cup? Yeah.
We have pizza now, too.
Yeah, pizza now.
It's so hard. I don't know how to do it.
Hit it higher.
Well, the middle one seems to be okay, so...
I think it's okay in the middle, so I'm going to hit it a little bit further out.
Wow, that's great.
Now, I'm going to have you put it on both sides of the board.
I'm going to roll it around with a type.
Board, board, that way, that way.
There, there, there.
Put them on both sides.
Let's roll it out with the pipe.
Have them put it in the middle.
Have them put it in the middle of the clay.
In the middle.
Grizzly, grizzly, grizzly.
That's right. That's right.
Oh, wow.
That's great.
If you keep going in the same direction, it's going to get longer and thinner.
So let's change the direction a little bit every once in a while.
That's what I said, and the board.
I see.
That's right.
I'll have him switch it out.
When it gets a little longer, I'd like to make it a little bigger at the end, so we'll do it on the floor.
I'll do it on the floor.
This is great. It's fun. It's like Tohoku.
It's great. It's fun for parents and kids.
It's fun for parents and kids.
I think it's fun for couples in a funk.
Matching cups and plates.
They sell matching cups and plates.
But you know how many pairs of matching cups go to Japan?
Yes, and you'll have matching cups and plates with other people.
So we'd be like four couples.
That's right.
But if we make them here, it's really just the two of us.
I like that. I like that.
That's a nice thing to say.
I'm still going to grow another year or two, so...
Good luck this time.
It's like you're putting all your weight on it.
Yes, sir.
Let's roll around.
Stretch it out. It'll make the adult thinner.
I've made some adjustments.
That's right.
How's the cup?
It's good.
How do you like it?
Do you think it should be a little bit rounded upside down?
It's better if it's rounded.
Roundness
It's a little less rounded.
Then...
That's good.
I haven't shown this in Japan.
Cue.
I brought something new.
I'll let you try it with this.
Okay.
It's a little rounded here, right?
Yes, it's rounded.
Match it here.
Oh, wow.
I put it on the inside, and I didn't move the hand that's holding it.
I rotate the bag with my other hand... and it starts to smear a little bit on the outside, so...
Like this.
Let's do it like this.
I'll do my best. Hold it tight with your hand.
Good luck.
That's right.
Now, if you look, it's a little rounder than before.
That's great. That's great.
I just did the bottom, so the bottom's a little bit out.
If you want it a little higher, you can move it a little bit higher.
If you want it a little higher, you can put it a little higher.
That's right, it's rounded.
Then put all your weight on it.
Put all your weight on it.
It's easier to stretch if you hold the middle of the pipe.
I see.
If the core becomes distorted, replace it immediately.
Let's cut the puller's end.
Let's cut it into a train.
Hold it like a pencil.
Cut your wrist as far as it will go.
Hold it at the lowest point.
Be careful not to move.
Here we go.
Yes, sir.
OK. Please raise it up.
Wow! Wow!
I ate!
That was fun.
Then, let's clean up your mouth a little bit so it doesn't get cut.
Okay.
Okay, now, do the dominant hand piece.
Can I ask you to turn it up?
Yes.
Put your thumbs here,
And that's to put it in the house.
Now, keep the clay between here.
Put it gently between them and turn it with your other hand.
The mouth doesn't move.
So that the corners will come off,
Let's do this for a few weeks to clean it up.
That won't cut the mouth, right?
Yes, it is.
Good.
Then we'll put the handles on later, at the very end.
I'll have them think about where they want to put the handle,
Just there,
Please leave it here.
Please make sure that the mouth is not cut off,
And write anything else you like on it,
Put a stamp on it and pull it out.
Okay.
Here you go.
What should I do?
What shape would you like?
I heard you like a round shape,
Or, you know, whatever suits your taste.
Or we'll cut it later.
Okay, I'll cut it.
What shape do you want?
In the shape of a face.
In the shape of the face.
In the shape of the face?
We're about the same.
I'm catching up.
Can I erase this once I stamp the pattern? You can erase it.
Yes, you can.
That's pretty good. I didn't tell you.
It works. It's a charm for lips.
But you don't like it?
Yes, it is. It's a little uncomfortable.
Like this. It's a little disgusting, isn't it?
It's a little disgusting.
You're eating with your own lips, and when you eat, you have lips.
Here, you know, oshinko.
What is that oshinko?
Oshinko.
Oh, that's shinko, that's cod roe, that's cod roe.
I don't like it.
That? It's nice, but...
A little.
What are you filming?
What do you think?
Maybe it's nice.
Cute.
Mmmmmm
Thank you for watching!
Make a bowl of tea.
You are humming.
Make the ears.
How deep do you want them?
Look at the depth of the dish.
Is it difficult?
It's more difficult than a plate, but not at all.
I guess it's the depth of the plate.
Is curry OK?
Curry?
It will be this size.
Hit this area.
Not at all.
Leave about one finger.
I see.
Now we have cut in.
Let's get this much depth and then put it in.
Sensei.
Yes.
Do you want to do this inside as well?
Yes. Give him a full round.
The cup is quite easily distorted,
It might be a good idea to do the inside while supporting the inside of the cup.
Yes.
That's right.
That's great.
It's a very good case.
Because it's good air.
And, you know, it's right now from the atmosphere.
The place where you guys are going to renovate.
You know.
You all should come.
Hey.
It's done.
Cute.
Next, let's give him a rim.
Yes, that's right.
Here's how to raise the edge.
First of all, let's give it a little bit of a gap from you, and give it a roundabout way.
That's right. While turning a little bit at a time.
Yes.
I will turn it around.
My hand goes around like this.
Oh, I see.
It's difficult.
It's difficult. This one.
Here.
Yes.
It's OK. This is about right.
Then..,
I'll have you put your finger on it.
Yes.
Not too close to the finger.
If it's too close, I'll put it too close.
Well, I'll read the thickness.
I see. A little bit at a time. That's right. That's right. You're good. Good.
Good.
And it's the hardest part.
Right?
I'll make you answer correctly. Too fast.
Yes.
OK.
Thank you very much.
Can I talk to you?
Yes.
Hey.
Can I play along?
Yes.
How can I expose it?
Talking chamado kurumaiië.
And this one.
Is that you?
Ah, ene
of
and
hand
discussion
Talk
Confirmation Did
al
I'm going to eat it.
Yes, so it's finished
Yes, sir.
Sir?
What is the next step?
I'd like to know.
And then leave your work as it is.
Yes, sir.
Colors.
Oh, colors.
Now that the plates and cups are complete
Next, we would like to decide on the colors.
I'd like to decide on the color.
Oh my gosh, what should I do?
There are so many colors!
So many colors!
I don't know what to do!
I'm so lost.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Tara, what are you gonna do?
What?
Sky blue, your favorite.
You can have that one, too.
I can do it.
Yes, sir.
Suddenly school
Suddenly High School
That reminds me of Ken Iwata in the interview.
Iwata
I like that video so much I keep watching it over and over.
What?
That interview video.
It's funny, isn't it?
Let's see...
I was just saying...
Yes, sir.
Yes, yes, yes.
We're done with the color selection.
We're done.
Yes, sir.
Hikaru Ritsuki
What did you choose?
I chose white.
Oh...
It's cute.
It's nice.
Yes, it is.
What did you choose, Miyu?
Let's see...
I chose 12 sky blue.
Yay!
Yes, I did
Using these colors
Yes, sir.
I think I'll make a plate
I think
I think so
I look forward to working with you.
I'm looking forward to working with you.
Thank you very much.
Yes, sir.
Number 280
dabei
Television
Trees
Thank you for watching!
Now I'm at the gift shop.
They sell a lot of tableware and stuff.
It's nice.
Very nice.
Oh, my God.
Look at this.
It's cute.
It's so cute.
I think Karen would really like it.
I think Karen would like it.
It's so cute.
That's so cute.
You get excited when you see nice tableware, don't you?
It does. I know.
Hit the taro stew bowl.
Give it to me for stewed potatoes.
Oh, a taro stew bowl?
A taro stew bowl.
I was hungry.
A rock!
Beer glass!
Nice!
Beer!
Cute!
Here's a couple.
I love it.
I highly recommend it.
Couple-friendly beer.
Yes, sir.
Okay, today...
At Chiemon's Masan
We had a pottery making experience!
It was fun!
It was fun.
We even got to try our hand at painting at the end.
at the end of the workshop.
This is in about two months
I'm really looking forward to seeing the finished product.
I'm really looking forward to seeing it finished!
I want to look sophisticated by then.
A little bit prettier.
I want to be a little bit prettier.
I want to be cute!
What are you going to drink soon after it's finished?
Well...
Recently...
I've learned to drink tea.
I drink a lot of tea at home.
I want to drink it.
I eat curry.
I'll eat it.
You made it for curry.
Yes, I did.
Then, everyone...
Come to Chiemon-gama
Why don't you come to Chiemon-gama and make plates for all kinds of food?
How about it?
See you all next time
Enjoy!
Bye bye!
How many minutes and seconds were good?
That was good.
What a good minute.
Thank you very much for your time.
Thank you for watching.